let's say that I have some things that I
假设我有一些需要walk狗和洗狗的东西
needed to like walk the dog and wash the
dishes and once each of the tasks is
菜肴，完成每项任务后，我希望能够将其标记为
done I want to be able to mark it as
completed now when we taught you this in
现在，当我们牢牢地教您这一点时，要做的是完成以下操作：
solidity is by doing the following we
store each task in array of strings and
将每个任务存储在字符串数组中，然后从索引创建映射
then we create a mapping from the index
of the array to a boolean value that we
将数组的值转换为完成任务后Marcus完成的布尔值
Marcus completed when the task is done
so for example the two tasks above would
因此，例如，上面的两个任务看起来像这样
look like this
here we're storing the two tasks walk
在这里，我们存储了两个任务，walk狗和洗碗
the dog and wash the dishes into the
array of strings and since the first
字符串数组，由于完成了第一个任务，我们将其标记为true，并且
task is done we mark it as true and the
second task is not yet finished so it is
第二项任务尚未完成，因此仍然是错误的，但这不是最重要的
still false however this is not the most
intuitive way of storing our data the
直观的方式来存储我们的数据，好消息是扎实的支持
good news is a solidity supports a
user-defined data type called strux
用户定义的数据类型称为strux，它将使我们能够存储更多数据
which will allow us to store data more
or less like this so in this video I'm
或更少这样，所以在这个视频中，我将向您展示如何创建结构
gonna show you how to create a struct
and how to get values from a struct and
以及如何从结构中获取值，然后如何更新它，您可以声明一个
then how to update it you can declare a
struct by starting with the keyword
以关键字struct开头，后跟关键字的名称
struct followed by the name of the
struct here we're going to call the
struct在这里，我们将调用该struct在所需的struct中进行操作
struct to do inside the struct we need
to store to the field a string of text
在字段中存储文本字符串和代表以下内容的布尔值
and a boolean value representing
completed so what we did here was we
完成，所以我们在这里要做的是定义要存储的数据类型
define the data type that's gonna store
us chain value and of attribute called
我们将链值和属性称为文本，并将布尔值存储在
text and store a boolean value in an
attribute called completed so this is
属性称为complete，因此这是您定义自己的自定义数据类型的方式
how you define your own custom data type
using a struct next let's go over how to
接下来使用结构，让我们讨论如何初始化结构，然后将其存储
initialize our struct and then store it
in our contract storage I want to store
在我们的合同存储中，我想在此合同中存储-会费清单，因此
a list of - dues in this contract so
let's create an array up to do and then
让我们创建一个要执行的数组，然后调用它执行操作以及执行操作的方式
call it to do and the way you would do
it is like this
就像这样，您首先声明数组的类型
you first declare the type of the array
in this case it will be to do and then
在这种情况下，将要做的事，然后加上方括号，这样可以说明
followed by brackets so this would tell
that we're creating array up to do's and
我们正在创建要执行的数组，然后它将成为公共状态
then it's gonna be a public state
variable so we're gonna put the public
变量，所以我们要在该关键字后面加上public关键字
keyword followed by the name of this
public state variable which we say we're
公共状态变量，我们说我们将调用它来在此处注意
going to call it to do notice here that
we just declared an array up to do where
我们只是声明一个要执行的数组，其中要做的数据类型就是我们定义的
the to do data type is what we define
here and it's not any built-in datatype
在这里，它不是任何内置数据类型，我们需要一个函数来
we're gonna need a function that will
create or new to do and then append it
创建或新建，然后将其附加到此数组中，我将其称为
into this array I'm gonna call this
function create and it's gonna taking a
函数创建，它将在函数内部获取一串文本
string of text and inside the function
we need to initialize a new to do and
我们需要初始化一个新的东西，然后将其推入数组中
then push it into the array now there
are two ways to initialize our struct
有两种初始化结构的方法，第一种方法是像调用它一样
the first way is to call it like a
function so it will be like this and
功能，它会像这样和[音乐]
[Music]
we're gonna push this newly created to
我们将把这个新创建的东西推入一个数组中，所以在这里我们进行初始化
do into an array so here we initialize
the new to do where the first argument
第一个参数对应于中的第一个元素的新操作
corresponds to the first element in the
definition of this job and the second
此作业的定义，第二个值对应于第二个元素
value corresponds to the second element
in the definition of the struct after
在初始化TD之后的结构定义中，我们立即
the TD is initialized we immediately
push it into the array up to this
将其推入数组直到另一种初始化结构的方式是
another way to initialize our struct is
like this
像这样
unlike the first way where the order of
与第一种方法不同，在这种情况下，参数的顺序很重要
the argument is important in this case
the order of argument is not important
参数的顺序并不重要，因此您可以切换参数
so you could switch around the argument
and this to do will still be valid so
而且这样做仍然有效，因此在这里我切换了
here I switched around the order of
texts and completed but this to do will
文字并完成，但是当您被击中时，此操作仍会立即初始化
still initialize now when you're struck
contains like five or more parameters
包含五个或更多参数，然后用这种方式初始化结构
then this way of initializing a struct
is more readable than the first way of
比第一种方式更具可读性
doing it
the third way of creating a struct is to
创建结构的第三种方法是初始化变量的类型
initialize a variable of the type of the
struct and then update the attributes so
结构，然后更新属性，例如，我们可以创建一个变量
for example we can create a variable of
type to do like this and then update
输入以执行此操作，然后在这种情况下更新该属性，
that attribute in this case we then have
to explicitly set the completed flag to
明确将completed标记设置为false，这是因为坚固性将其设置为
false this is because solidity sets it
to its default values so this is a
为其默认值，因此这是在以下情况下初始化结构的有用方法：
useful way to initialize our struct when
you're struck contains many attributes
您被包含许多属性或包含复杂数据的内容而震惊
or when it contains complex data and you
just want solidity to set it to its
只是希望将其设置为默认值，所以这是三种方式
default values so these are three ways
to initialize our struct positional key
初始化我们的结构位置键值映射，然后对其进行声明并
value mapping and then declare it and
then update it now that we have a
然后更新它，现在我们有一个功能可以创建这些，然后
function to create to those and then
store it in this array next let's create
将其存储在此数组中接下来，让我们创建一个函数以获取那些
a function to get the to those out of
this array we will name this function
这个数组我们将这个函数命名为get，它将接受索引
get and it's going to take in the index
of the array
数组的[音乐]
[Music]
and it's gonna return the to do now in
它会以其他编程语言返回现在可以执行的操作
other programming languages you can
return a stroke like this however in
返回这样的笔划，但稳固性为0.5，这不是有效的功能
solidity 0.5 this is not a valid feature
so instead we'll need to explicitly
所以相反，我们需要显式声明潮汐以返回我们要去的地方
declare the tides to return we're going
to return the string stored in our to do
返回存储在我们要做的结构中的字符串，然后返回布尔值
struct and then also the boolean value
that represents whether to do is
代表该操作是否完成，接下来我们需要获取
complete it or not next we need to get
the to do stored in this array at this
将要存储在此索引处的数组中，因此我们将声明一个
index so we're going to declare a
variable that references the to do that
变量，该变量引用存储在此和X处的方法以及您的方式
is stored at this and X and the way you
do it is you declare the type of data
是因为您声明要执行的数据类型，因为这将是
which is to do since it's going to be a
variable that's stored in storage we're
存储在存储中的变量，我们将声明为存储，然后
going to declare as storage and then the
name of the variable we elect to do and
我们选择执行的变量的名称，该名称将等于
this is going to equal to those at the
end X and we return the two attributes
结束X，我们返回两个属性文本并完成存储在此操作
text and completed stored in this to do
like this so this illustrates how to get
这样，这说明了如何获取存储在状态中的结构
our struct that is stored in a state
variable you first declare the type of
在这种情况下，您首先要声明数据类型的变量
the data in this case it is to do
followed by the keyword storage since
后跟关键字storage，因为数据存储在状态变量中
the data is stored in a state variable
and then followed by the name of the
然后输入变量名称并访问属性
variable and to access the attributes
that is stored in the struct you do it
它存储在结构中，您可以像下面这样操作，让我们来看看如何
like this next let's go over how to
update your struct
更新您的结构，我希望能够更新的文本
I want to be able to update the text of
the to do and then marques completed so
要做，然后完成字幕，所以我们要创建两个函数
we're going to create two function want
update the text and another function
更新文字，另一个功能市场已经完成，我们要命名
market has completed we're gonna name
the first function update and it's gonna
第一次函数更新，它将接受数组的索引是否
take in the index of the array whether
to do this toy followed by the new text
做这个玩具，然后更新新文本以及您访问它的方式
to update and the way you access it to
do I already explained the earlier so
我早先已经解释过了吗，所以我只复制并粘贴代码
I'm just gonna copy and paste the code
here and to update the to do you do it
在这里并更新，您可以这样做吗，所以在这里，我们要做
like this so here we get the to do and
then update the text attribute to our
然后将text属性更新为从中传入的新文本值
new text value that was passed in from
our function the code update the
我们的功能代码更新completed属性将是相似的
completed attribute is gonna be similar
to the code here so we're first gonna
到这里的代码，所以我们首先要复制，然后将代码粘贴到这里
copy and then paste the code here I'm
gonna name this function double
将这个函数命名为双完成，只需要索引
completed it's only gonna need the index
of the array and nothing else and to
数组的其他内容，并更新完成的属性，我们将
update the completed attribute we'll
just reassign it to the opposite of the
只需将其重新分配为当前完成值的反面即可，因此，如果
current completed value so if the
current value of the completed is true
完成的当前值是true，那么更新的完成将是false
then the updated completed will be false
and if the current value of the complete
如果complete的当前值为false，则将新值设置为
is false then the new one will be set to
true now let's compile it and put our
是的，现在让我们编译一下，然后将我们的两个家伙放在区块链上
two dudes on the blockchain first I'm
going to
要做到这一点，我需要洗碗，
to do this I need to wash the dishes and
walk the dog we can check that our to
狗，我们可以检查我们那些被保存到合同中的人
those been stored into the contract by
calling get notice that solidity also
呼吁注意，团结也为我们创造了完全相同的吸气剂，因此
created the same exact getter for us so
actually we didn't need to write this
实际上，我们不需要编写此函数，因为自动自动生成
function since solidity automatically
creates getters for us but it's useful
为我们创造吸气剂，但了解如何从
to know how to get values out of a
struct especially when you want to
结构，尤其是当您要自定义要使用的数据时
customize which data that you're gonna
be returning next let's try updating the
接下来返回，让我们尝试更新，以便将第二个更新为
to do so I'm gonna update the second to
do so the index will be one and instead
这样做的索引将是一个，而不是walking狗，我要walk
of walking the dog I'm gonna walk the
cat and we can check that out to those
cat，我们可以通过调用get或to来检查是否已更新
been updated by calling either get or to
lose and it returns walk the cat once I
输了，它返回walk猫，一旦我完成walking猫的动作，我要标记它
finish walking my cat I'm gonna mark it
as completed the index of the to do is
完成后，要做的索引是1，然后点击切换完成，我可以
one and I hit toggle completed I can
check that the two dudes been updated by
通过再次调用检查两个家伙是否已更新，现在返回
calling yet again and now it returns
true now I forgot to mention this
是的，现在我忘了提起这个，但是请注意，
earlier but notice that the output of
the two dues on the bottom is a little
底部的两个会费与这里的会费有些不同，因此
bit different from the ones here so the
output here is saying that the text
这里的输出是说text属性被走了哦，猫和
attribute is walked Oh cat and the
completed attribute is false
completed属性为false，而最重要的是，
whereas up on top it's saying that the
first return value is walk the cat and
第一个返回值是walk猫，第二个返回值是true，因此
the second return value is true so
before we go I'm gonna show you how to
在我们开始之前，我将向您展示如何将输出作为键值返回
return the output as a key value like
this and the way to do it is to name
这样做的方法是这样命名您的输出
your output like this
let's recompile and redeployed contract
让我们重新编译并重新部署合同
and now you can see here that
现在您可以在此处看到将文本whopper cat转换为已完成
turn the text whopper cat and completed
equal to false being able to return an
等于false能够返回输出，因为键值变得非常大
output as a key value becomes extremely
useful when your smart contract
当您的智能合约与其他程序交互时很有用
interacts with other programming
languages instead of remembering that
语言，而不是记住第一个值代表
the first value represents the text of
the to do and the second value
要执行的操作，第二个值表示是否要执行的操作
represents whether the to do is
completed or not you'll get a map where
完成与否，您会得到一张地图，其中的文字等同于走路的猫和
the text is equal to walk the cat and
completed is equal to false so you won't
完成等于假，因此您不必记住命令的顺序
have to remember the order of the
outputs well that's all I got for this
输出得很好，这就是我为这部影片所获得的一切，感谢您的收看和观看
video thanks for watching and see you in
the next video
下一个视频